BERTRAND DE MONTETY

ABOUT ME

Currently software engineer on embedded system products at Sagemcom. With over 3 years of experience, I've developed professional proficiency in the UK, Abu Dhabi and France. Graduated with a master degree in computer science and specialised in System, Security and Network at EPITA in Paris.

EDUCATION

Master Degree, specialised in security, network and system, EPITA, Paris 2015 - 2017

Major courses: network, operating system, computer science, cybersecurity, forensic, cryptography, maths.

Minor course: economic intelligence.

Undergraduate courses, EPITA, Paris 2011 - 2015

Main courses: computer science, algorithm, maths, electronic.

SKILLS

Languages C, C++, Bash, SQL, Python, Java

Skills Software development, technical support to clients and project teams, Agile process, debug, tests.

Tools Linux, Git, Jira, Confluence, CMake, buildroot.

Knowledge OS fundamentals, network (TCP IP stack), security systems.

EXPERIENCE

Software engineer at Sagemcom

London, UK

Oct 2018 - Now

Software development and local technical support to the Youview's teams to create a new set-top box for our client, British Telecom (BT).

- Development and integration: telemetry agents (data collection, diagnostics daemons).
- Technical support: team representative providing help onsite for the client and partner companies, following all the technical topics (dev tasks, bugs, deliveries, demo, coordination testing), lead calls, local UK support for Sagemcom project and pre-sales teams.
- Technology stack used : embedded system, C, Linux, agile development tools.

Software engineer at OTG

Abu Dhabi, UAE

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

C++ development of a multithreaded forensic application, designed to facilitate large scale of network data investigations, by performing a deep analysis (DPI) and enrichment over these network data.

- Responsibilities : development, tests, coordination, deployment.
- Coordination: with the others teams working on the back-end/front-end.
- **Deployment and support**: installation of the solution on the customers side and onsite support.
- Technology stack used: C++, C, Linux, Python, Bash, SQL.

Web developer internship at NSIT System

Paris, France

Sep 2015 - Dec 2015

Internship in a IT services company (R&D department). Java EE development, creation of a web portal for banking application. Agile software development in a group of 10 developers.

- Responsibilities: front-end / back-end, tests with JUnit, presentation client.
- Technology stack used : JAVA, SQL, JavaScript, JQuery, Jenkins.

HOBBIES

Music : Guitar, piano Sports : Judo, boxing Others : History, travels